The main reason why you're losing money
in the markets, which is about to sound
crazy, it's because you're literally
entering trades at the wrong place.
Plain and simple. It could be a great
trade setup that you analyzed or it can
even be a bad trade. But the truth of
the matter is that the entire setup is
completely wrong if you are not taking
it at the right place. And that's why I
brought David here. David over the
course of the next 30 days is going to
be living with me until I can teach him
how to understand and execute a
profitable strategy where he is going to
then turn this into his new main source
of income. Now, over the course of the
next 30 days, David is going to be
living here and we're going to turn
$1,000 into
$100,000. We're going to be documenting
everything, the before, the during, the
after of his whole entire journey and
how he goes through it. It's going to be
his first account flip and his first
time. Yes, David is a stranger. Now,
over time, we've gotten to know each
other, but about two and a half weeks
ago, I set a application for somebody to
be part of this life-changing
opportunity. After 50,000 applicants,
traveling to multiple different states,
and identifying different potential
candidates, we're left with David, young
guy, worked two jobs, and now we're
here. This is going to be one of the
many videos that I am going to be
teaching David how to execute and learn
this strategy perfectly. And we're going
to be documenting it and sharing it with
you guys completely for free. So you can
follow along and learn from his journey
so you're actually able to replicate his
exact same results. And the best part is
that it's free. So, in this particular
video, we're going to learn how to
properly do a top- down analysis so you
know when, where, and how to enter a
trade and avoid those wickouts, avoid
those unnecessary draw downs, and even
avoid taking a loss. In order for you to
take a trade and it be a profitable
trade, you don't need to predict where
the market is going to be every single
hour of the day, every single day of the
month, every single week of the year.
The key is you need to know when to
enter and when to not enter, right?
Being involved in the markets and trying
to predict every move, it's not going to
make you any money. You have to know
where to enter and that goes directly
with identifying the structure of the
trend. Knowing where is the high and
where is the low of the market, finding
a proper area of interest, which is
going to be key to executing at the
correct point. And lastly, when should
you actually enter this trade? All of
that we're going to break down in this
video right now. So, first things first,
to do a proper top down analysis, you
pretty much have to do exactly as it
says, do a top down analysis. So, we're
going to start off from the weekly time
frame, work our way down all the way to
the 15minute, meaning weekly, daily, 4
hour, 2 hour, 1 hour, 30 minute, 15
minute. Now, every single one of these
time frames has a completely different
purpose in this top down analysis. But
the first step is to understand is the
weekly bullish or is it bearish? Is the
daily bullish or the daily bearish?
4-hour bullish, 4-hour bearish, so on
all the way up into the 15minut time
frame. Now once you have all the
different time frames and then there you
understand where the majority of these
time frames are headed decision on where
you should take a trade should be very
easy. If five of these time frames are
bullish for example and two of them are
bearish. Does it make more sense to sell
or to buy? Well that actually depends on
the type of time frames that are
indicating to you if it's bullish or
bearish. All that's going to make sense
in just a second. So coming into the
charts, first things first, you would
look at this market and then you would
immediately as a beginner trader
identify that this market can
potentially be bullish. So this weekly
time frame maybe you can identify as
creating highs and lows, higher highs,
higher lows, and you would see that it's
bullish. Mhm. And you would actually be
wrong. This market is indeed bearish.
This is a higher high, higher low,
higher high, higher low, higher high.
lower low and right now we are
potentially creating a lower high. This
market shifted the structure at this
high point right here. Meaning to start
off with our top down analysis, the
weekly time frame is bearish. So now
that we understand that the weekly time
frame is bearish, we go to the daily
time frame. Daily time frame, we would
assume just by looking at it that it's
bullish just because it's creating highs
and lows. But there you would be wrong.
Once again, when you look at the market
to identify if it's bullish or bearish,
you look at the higher highs and higher
lows. The market structure, these
elbows, high, low, high, low. Basically,
every single point in the market where
it had a shift, this market would
consider that a structure point. Every
single one of these elbows is a
structure point. And this market has
created many of them. Now, if you
answered that it's bearish, I want you
to know exactly why it's bearish. It's
not bearish because of this right here.
It's bearish because this right here is
the lower high. And then this point down
here is the lower low. Meaning this is
the lower high. This is the lower low.
We haven't body closed below it. So it's
there's no new lower low. We haven't
closed above it because there's no
higher high. So it's not bullish. So the
daily time frame is bearish because of
this structure point here. Not because
of this head and shoulders pattern right
here. Not because of this lower high and
because of this lower low. That would be
false. It's bearish because of those
high moves. So you get that, right? I
got you. So the daily time frame, we
would add it here as bearish as well.
Correct. Now we're basically going to do
the same thing on the 4 hour, 2 hour, 1
hour, 30 minute, 15 minute, 4 hour time
frame. Very clear indication that we can
potentially tell that this market is
currently bearish. You can as well see
how the market was creating highs. Then
we shifted to the downside. I personally
would not count this point right here as
a structure point. This right here is
not a clean structure point to me. So I
would not count this as a structure
point. This would be the lower high and
lower low. Many would get confused.
Count this as a lower low, lower high,
and then a lower low. For me, one
candlestick of a retracement is not
enough for it to be considered an elbow.
I would need for it to be something a
bit more. If you notice, candlestick
retraces like this with two or more
candlesticks are a bit more stronger and
cleaner and more respected. So, this
4hour time frame as well, it is bearish.
Bearish. Now, we go down to the 2-hour
time frame. Two-hour time frame, we are
struck with a bit of a different type of
market structure. We have a very clean
lower low, lower high, lower low. we
shift bullish, higher high and higher
low. So, as of right now, the two-hour
time frame is bullish. We body
candlestick above this structure point.
Then this right here becomes the higher
high and then this becomes the higher
low. We're yet to break above or under
that. So, we're still bullish. Okay. So,
you get that, right? Yeah. So, this is
the first time frame that is bullish.
That is bullish. Correct. And it breaks
out of the pattern that we were
currently in, which is fine. Right.
Right now we're just understanding where
the market is. The 1 hour time frame,
very similar situation. This would be
the higher low. This would be the higher
high. We yet to break above or below it.
So the 1 hour time frame is
indeed bullish as
well. Then we go down to our 30 minute
time frame and 30 minute time frame as
of right now is bearish. So you can see
how this was creating lower low, lower
high, lower low, lower high, lower low,
lower high, lower low. We went bullish
and then we shifted bearish and right
now it's creating almost what looks like
to be a double top. So right now the
30-minut time frame is bearish. Bearish
too. And lastly, the 15minute one. Yeah,
definitely least. Last, usually people
say last but not least, the 15-minut
time frame is the least cuz it's the
weakest time frame. It's not the one
that is the strongest or most respected.
So, we don't really care for it that
much. I use it a bit for my entry
signals, but we'll save that towards the
end of the video. 15-minute time frame.
Right now, we were creating lower lows,
lower highs, lower lows, shifted
bullish, higher high, higher low. Kind
of skip all of that. Higher low, and
higher high. 15-minut time frame is
indeed bullish. And then lastly,
15-minut time frame is bullish. Meaning
we have a total of one, two, three, four
time frames bearish and then we have
three three time frames. So, right off
the bat, it makes more sense to sell and
to buy. But let's say it was for example
four time frames bullish and then three
time frames bearish. Would that make
sense to buy? Not really. Because the
lower time frames being in one direction
doesn't mean that the higher time frames
are going to go in that direction as
well. So for me, whenever I go take a
trade and ever I go do top analysis,
what makes the most sense is to have the
highest time frames going in that
direction. So if the weekly is bearish,
daily is bearish and 4 hours bearish, I
want to continue to trade with those
markets to have a higher probability to
trade setup. Now, can I be interested in
buys because these lower time frames are
in one direction? Sure. But it's not as
strong as a probability. The higher time
frames, the more respected the market
is, the lower the time frame, the less
the market respected is. Okay. Okay. You
get that? Yeah, I understand. Yeah.
Okay. So now that we understand that the
majority of the time frames are going to
the downside when we are done with this
part of the top analysis we move on to
the next phase which is looking for area
of interest. So we cannot enter a trade
without an area of interest. I'm going
to I'm going to repeat that. We can have
all these time frames bearish or all
these time frames bullish, but if you
don't have a proper area of interest,
you cannot take the trade take the trade
at all. Area of interest is going to be
the most crucial points on where you're
actually going to enter. For example, if
let's say right now we are surfers,
right? We're going to go to the ocean to
surf. We can see a bunch of waves being
created going to one direction to the
shore. and you want to go out there and
surf, but if you don't know where you're
going to enter on that wave, it's no
good. You basically can't do anything.
Let's say right now there's a basketball
game going on and the ball is out of
bounds, you can't play the game at all
because the ball is out of bounds. You
can only play the game when the ball is
in bounds. It's in the game. Right now,
if the trade is completely bearish and
there's no proper area of interest, the
ball is not in the game. There's like
the game is not happening. You only take
a trade after you have a proper area of
interest. So the way area of interest is
identified is very simple to simplify
very quickly. We have here a market that
is a bullish market. Bullish market what
we are anticipating for price to do is
have a retracement. This retracement
stop at some given time and point before
then having the push to the upside. Our
job as traders is to predict when is
this stop going to stop. So then we can
have our entry right around here. So
then the trade from here can then have
the push to the upside. That's our job
to predict when is this pullback going
to stop before it actually has the push
up. So you can almost anticipate when
this pullback is going to happen to
perfection based off of an area of
interest. So now we understand this
market's bullish. Let's say this is the
daily time frame for example. we were
allowed to find an area of interest
which is a point where the market has
respected multiple times in theory a
minimum of three times. So let's just
add another structure point here right
here. So we can have our minimum of
three touches. And yes, it could count
even if you have structure points above.
This has one, two, three, three, four,
four. Right. So this is a valid area of
interest. So we would expect is for
price to have a retracement into this
area, retest it, head to the upside.
Okay. And what's the minimum like
touching points that we need? So it's
it's a minimum of three. So you're going
to have three points above, three points
below, a total of three points. So let's
say for example, one above, one under,
and one above. Or you can have all three
of them under. As long as there's three
points of that area, it's a valid area.
You got that? Yeah, I got it. Okay. So
if we were to go to, for example, let's
say the weekly time frame, weekly time
frame, we would identify where we are
right now. And if we were to look left,
we would not really see any price action
for
about 10 years. But even then, this line
right here, we have one, two, and we go
back to current price. And then we have
three. That's three
touches. Bear with me. We go down to the
daily time frame. And then in the daily
time frame, we would do the exact same
thing, but in a much more detailed
version with what we're dealing with
right now. So, for example, we can spot,
let's say, a zone like this. Here we
were to have one, two, and then three.
That's a valid area of interest. If you
were to look at the market like
this, one, 2, 3, 4. Valid. Very valid.
You look at it like this, there's
nothing there. It's not valid. I
personally the furthest I like to look
back when identifying these areas of
interest is anywhere in between one to
three years. That's the furthest I ever
like to look back recently with the way
the new markets have changed. It's just
we want to make sure we're executing a
trade where the market has respected
recently, not 10 years ago. The world's
in a different place 10 years ago. the
markets are there right now and I want
to make sure that the price is very
relevant to the most recent. So our
second thing is identifying an area of
interest and this area of interest is
very well respected. Now at this point
that we have officially identified the
area of interest, it's officially game
on. So everything we've done up to this
point is just understanding where the
market is. At no point have we executed
the strategy right now. At no point have
we have done anything that's out of the
normal, right? All all we've done is
just read the market. Yeah. Now is when
we're going to start applying our
strategy to potentially execute this
trade. A very simple analogy is let's
say that you're a surfer right now is at
the point where you would go out to the
ocean and then go and get on to your
board. Mhm. Now, a very big mistake that
a lot of surfers make is they'll pull up
to the beach, they'll go out to the
ocean, and they wait in the ocean for a
wave. Okay. What happens? They get eaten
by a shark. The current takes them far
away. I don't know. I'm not a surfer.
Are you a surfer? No, I'm not a surfer.
an analogy, right? So, it's a very high
risk approach. Unless risk, right? You
don't have to be out there in the water
for the wave for you to surf the wave.
You could be on the beach safely under
an umbrella, not getting burnt. When you
see the wave approaching, then you can
then go out into the water. You swim to
it and then you you surf the wave. Is
there a possibility that of you missing
it? Sure, it's fine. It's normal, but
you're minimizing your risk. If you do
not have your trade be at your area of
interest, why would you go in and enter
a trade? It simply makes no sense.
That's right. If you don't have the wave
right there at that given moment, why
would you be waiting in the water? It's
just very high risk. It only makes sense
to execute the trade when it's at your
area of interest. It only makes sense to
ride a wave when it's ready to be
ridden. There's no reason to be
overexposed for no reason. Now, I want
to make sure you understand this is so
crucial and so key because some traders,
they would do their analysis, they would
do the top analysis decently. They'll
find a decent area of interest and then
they'll feel like the market owes them
something because they've analyzed the
market. You got to make sure that you
can analyze the market, put so much time
into it, and it mean nothing. Okay? That
you have to be completely emotionally
detached from that trade. Yes, you got
that right. I got it. It's very key. So,
now that you understand that you don't
have to be in the ocean waiting for the
wave, you can wait for it at the beach.
You want to make sure that you know what
you're waiting for, right? Like you want
to have your binocular set so you can
see the wave. You can be waiting for
something specific. Correct. That's
exactly what we would do here once price
is approaching or reaching the area of
interest. So for example, let's say this
trade at this point once this trade
broke this neckline and or this area of
interest. This is where the majority of
traders would just want to get involved
right away because they feel like
they're going to be right about the
direction which they're right. Right.
This the majority of the time frames are
bearish. You have a head and shoulders.
you have many different formations are
identifying that this trade should
continue to go down rather than up.
Okay, so this is where the big mistake
comes in because they're getting
involved too early, too quick. Okay,
just because the water and the currents
are going in one way, you don't want to
go in right away. You still have to wait
for your trade. You have to wait for
your entry. This is where you would wait
for a retracement, which is where price
would then come back into this area. And
now when you're in this area is where
then you're going to wait for the most
important and most crucial point which
is going to be your entry signal. The
entry signal is very much overlooked
among the traders in the industry and
they overlook it or they underlook it.
They they never find the perfect medium.
They either over complicate it or
oversimplify it.
If you're looking to sell a trade at an
area of interest, you need to have as
many possible confirmations that the
trade is going to sell. So for example,
the 4hour time frame. So let me actually
take a step back, right? Weekly, daily,
4hour time frame. These are the three
time frames to identify the trend of the
markets. Okay. The 2 hour, 1 hour, 30
minute, and 15 minutes are used to
actually enter the trade. Mhm. Now,
these lower time frames are used to
enter the trade based off of the
direction of the higher time frames.
Okay, you understood that, right? Yeah.
If the higher time frames are bearish,
we use the lower time frames to enter
those cells. So, if we go down to the 30
minute right now, for example, and we're
looking for sells, how are we going to
sell? If the 30 time frame, if the
30-minut time frame is bullish, we're
creating lower lows, lower highs, lower
lows, lower highs. And now we shifted
bullish. So if we're looking to sell and
our entry signal time frame is bullish,
how are we going to sell? Doesn't make
any sense. We need to only sell when the
lower time frames match our higher time
frames. So this is where the even though
the wave is getting close to be formed
and you're itching to go out there and
go ride it, it's not ready yet, right?
Because the wave is just on its way to
the beach. hasn't decided if it wants to
go east or if it wants to go west. And
you want it to go west because that's
where all the girls are on the beach or
whatever surfers look for whenever they
go surf. Yeah, there's a big nice wave
loading up, but you don't know what way
it's going to go. This is literally
setting up the perfect
pre-market setup for that to happen,
right? So, what price does when it
reaches the area of interest has an
accumulation. This is one of the major
things that I like to see because it
shows me that it's struggling to break
through this area, which clearly
whenever we're above this area, we
struggle, we have a push up. Whenever we
are under this area, we struggle and we
push down. Now that we're here again, I
can simply anticipate for the exact same
thing to happen. So, this is the higher
low. This is the higher high. In order
for me to take the cell, I would need to
wait for a shift of structure. And this
is where we would remain extremely
patient and wait for the ship to
structure. This is two, three hours that
have just gone by that we're just making
it seem very quickly. And that's where
the difficulty comes in from this, the
waiting game, of course, sitting on your
hands and waiting for what you need to
get done happen. So at this point, we're
still not taking the trade. The market
is still bullish and it's not giving us
our entry signal. You need to wait for
the shift to structure. So at this point
that minor body candlestick that closed
below that structure point that's it
that's our entry signal that is our
entry signal that now the 30 minute time
frame has shifted and now it's in
correlation with the higher time frame.
So now weekly, daily, 4hour are bearish
and so is the 30 minute time frame which
is an entry signal time frame for
example which is an added confluence
that would then lead us to understand
that now the 30 minute is following the
higher time frames. So we have the
higher time frames bearish, we have a
solid area of interest and then we also
have our trade at the area of interest
giving us a shift structure inside of
it. Like you're literally creating a
perfect setup that it simply makes more
sense for this to go down than up.
Because at the end of the day, the
market's going to do two things. Go up
or down. Yeah. We just got to figure out
why it makes one. Yeah. Which one most
famous? Yeah. Which one makes more sense
for it to go down or up? This right
here, off of everything I've just said,
you could explain to your grandma and
they're going to literally understand
it. Yeah. So once price has the break of
the structure area, you would then wait
for either a bearish engulfing
confirmation, an evening star, you can
look for any reversal patterns like head
and shoulders, double tops, anything
that confirms now that it's shifted
bearish that it's going to continue that
momentum because one thing is shifting
bearish and another thing is continuing
that momentum. And then here we shift
bearish and we simply continue that
momentum. Now you can see here how this
structure went from being bullish to
creating higher highs to now being lower
low, lower high, lower low, lower high.
Yeah, I see. So it literally goes from
having the bearish move. It goes bullish
to have the retracement to have the
retest of the area of interest and then
it shifts and then it continues to move
down. It just it's simple waves but not
the actual surfing ones. You're just
like trading waves. More fun ones. These
to me they're more fun because they make
me money, you know? I'm not prone to
getting eaten by a shark, you know.
Yeah. And now this is one of the trades
that I'm actively in right now. And I am
very confident in this trade to continue
heading to the downside. Price action is
rejecting. And as soon as I enter the
trade, I follow the slogan. I mean, set
and forget like forget. All I do is just
let the trade either do one or two
things. I let the trade either hit my
stop loss or I let the trade hit my
takerit. I don't do anything in between.
And you never change the never never
because if you change the trade, you're
changing your strategy essentially
because whatever you took at whatever
given point met a strategy and it made
sense at that point. That means that the
trade still makes sense. Just because it
doesn't go to your take profit right
away doesn't mean the trade is not
valid. If the trade sometimes it'll take
a day or two or three and if that's what
it takes, that's what it takes. I always
make sure that my stop loss is placed
above the previous high just in case if
For whatever reason, we now body
candlestick close above this area. We
are completely wrong because since we
had the shift to structure when I
entered the trade on the 30 minute for
me, I identified this to be the lower
high and I identified that this be the
new lower low at the time of me watching
this market. This was the lower high.
This was the lower low. If this price
from this given point body candlestick
above this structure point, technically
would be bullish and it's destined to
continue going to the upside. So I only
place my stop loss at an area where if
it gets hit, it's completely wrong.
Okay, this is very key% very key. Very
key. And then I simply place my
takeprofit a little bit below the next
structure point where I believe that
daily time frame is destined to go. Stop
loss placement is so key. Can't even
imagine. Okay. And what if for example
uh the trade goes so well that we can
put the stop loss or a take profit was?
Yeah. So that's called moving your stops
or trail stops, however you want to call
it. That's something that I sometimes
tend to do. You could do it. It's a
great way on how to continue to set and
forget. But I would try and only do that
on trades that have higher potentials of
risk-to-reward. Right? So, if a trade
has a, for example, this trade, I only
see it to have a 1:2 risk-to-reward, for
example. But if you have a trade that
has a potential for it to be a 1 to4,
sure, once the trade hits your original
take-profit of a 1:2, you could move
your stop loss there, worst case, takes
you out of the 1 to2. I personally don't
really do this myself. I see other
people successfully do it. I would
recommend either takes you out of your
full take profit or takes you out of
your full stop-loss. I wouldn't modify
moving your stop loss to a random area
where you enter the trade, which has
nothing to do with the market structure.
You're prone to getting wicked out at
break even. And for example, like let's
say right now when this trade was a
little bit into profit and I would have
put it at break even. Price would have
just taken me out at break even and now
continue heading to the downside.
Putting it at break even or moving your
stops has nothing to do with how the
market moves. It's just you wanting to
cover your risk. And you cover your risk
by pre-calculating it beforehand. You
don't have to not want to lose money
after you take a trade. Okay. But it's a
great way of thinking. That's being
conservative. I think that's great. And
you know what? I love the fact that you
asked that last question there because
it it shows me that you're like catching
up pretty fast. And it's very key that
you understand to make money in trading,
it's not all about added risk. make
money by preserving your money and being
strategic with your risk. Not about
risking more. It's about knowing when to
risk and knowing when to not risk. And
the crazy part is that this is literally
just one of the many videos that we're
going to be doing with David. And his
journey has been honestly accelerating a
lot faster than I imagined. And we're
sharing all of his journey completely
for free. We're documenting it in real
time. His trades before, during, the
after. And by the time you're watching
this recording, you can still watch
everything and catch up and still even
replicate his results. In the link
below, we have created a library where
you can get access to this completely
for free and you can see what David did
to be part of this journey and how you
can replicate it for yourself. I hope
you guys enjoyed this video. This is one
of many that we are going to be creating
for you guys completely for free. Make
sure to hit that like and subscribe
button and I'll see you guys in the next
video.